Be fierce. Be wild. Be free.
Wolfwalkers is a animation, family, adventure film directed by Tomm Moore.
In a time of superstition and magic, when wolves are seen as demonic and nature an evil to be tamed, a
young apprentice hunter comes to Ireland with her father to wipe out the last pack.
But when she saves a wild native girl, their friendship leads her to discover the world of the
Wolfwalkers and transform her into the very thing her father is tasked to destroy.
Robyn Goodfellowe (voice), played by Honor Kneafsey.
Mebh Óg MacTíre (voice), played by Eva Whittaker.
Robyn's Father, Bill Goodfellowe (voice), played by Sean Bean.
Lord Protector (voice), played by Simon McBurney.
Sean Óg (voice), played by Tommy Tiernan.
Mebh's Mother, Moll MacTíre (voice), played by Maria Doyle Kennedy.
Wolfwalkers is a 2020 independent animated fantasy adventure film directed by Tomm Moore and Ross Stewart, and is the third instalment
in Moore's "Irish Folklore Trilogy", following his previous films The Secret of Kells (2009) and Song of the Sea (2014).
An international co-production led by Cartoon Saloon and Mélusine Productions, the film
premiered at the 2020 Toronto International Film Festival on 12 September.
It was released theatrically in Ireland on 2 December
2020 and in France on 16 December 2020.
Wolfwalkers follows the story of Robyn Goodfellowe, a young apprentice hunter who arrives in Ireland
with her father during a time of superstition and magic to wipe out the last wolf pack.
While exploring the forbidden lands outside the city walls, Robyn befriends a free-spirited girl, Mebh, a
member of a mysterious tribe rumoured to have the ability to turn into wolves by night.
As they search for Mebh's missing mother, Robyn uncovers a secret that draws her further into the enchanted
world of the Wolfwalkers and risks turning into the very thing her father is tasked to destroy.
The film stars the voices of Honor Kneafsey, Eva Whittaker, Sean Bean, Simon
McBurney, Maria Doyle Kennedy, Tommy Tiernan, Jon Kenny and John Morton.
It won several awards including the Satellite Award for Best Animated or Mixed Media Feature and five Annie
Awards including Best Director for Moore and Stewart and Best Independent Animated Feature.
It also received the nominations for Best Animated Feature Film at the
Academy Awards, Golden Globe Awards and BAFTA Awards.
The film explores themes of friendship, wolf, magic, fairy tale, shapeshifting.